Guide to the Elizabeth Willis DeHuff Collection of American Indian Art
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Unidentified [Navajo women cooking]. Box 14, Folder 170
Unidentified [Navajo family eating under awning]. Box 14, Folder 171
Unidentified [Navajo men chasing after woman]. Box 14, Folder 172
Unidentified [Navajo women playing game with stones]. Box 14, Folder 173
Unidentified [Five Indian religious figures]. Box 14, Folder 174
Unidentified [Navajo woman washing man's hair]. Box 14, Folder 175
Unidentified [Navajo group sleeping inside]. Box 14, Folder 176
Unidentified [Navajo woman hitching horses to a wagon]. Box 14, Folder 177
Unidentified [Navajo sheep farm]. Box 14, Folder 178
Unidentified [Navajo feast]. Box 14, Folder 179
Unidentified [Navajo wagon train camped]. Box 14, Folder 180
Unidentified "Illustration for Katchinas in Holland's Magazine." Box 15, Folder 185
Unidentified "Katchinas for August." Box 15, Folder 186
Art, American; Cheyenne art; Indians of North America -- Pictorial works; Kiowa art; Navajo art; Pueblo art; Drawings -- United States; Paintings -- United States; Teachers -- New Mexico; DeHuff, Elizabeth Willis, 1886-1983; DeHuff, John David; Santa Fe Indian School
- Artworks, 1917-1945; Series I; 7.6; (14 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The artworks, which are mainly gouache and watercolor, include pencil, crayon, and ink sketches. Where possible, titles for works have been transcribed. In cases where no caption was present, a description of the work has been supplied in brackets by the processing archivist or student assistant. Thirteen of the pieces in the collection contain art on the recto and verso of a single sheet, or are multiple works on a single sheet; titles are noted or supplied for both images. Rounded dimensions (h x w) for the unmatted art works are also provided. At the end of each description statement, a number indicates the sequence of the item in earlier finding aids.
  A listing of the works, indexed by artist name, follows the box and folder listing.
  Arrangement
  Series I. Artworks is arranged into four sub-series according to the physical dimensions of the original art work: 15.25" x 11.75" Boxes, 17.5" x 11.75" Boxes, 20.5" x 17.5" Boxes, and a 22.75" x 28.75" Box. Within each box size, works are arranged alphabetically by artist name, with individual works of an artist listed chronologically. Thirty-five unattributed works are listed and housed at the end of each box size's alphabetical sequence.
  - 15.25" x 11.75" Boxes
    - Atencio, Gilbert Benjamin (Wah Peen). [Male and female San Ildefonso Basket Dancers]. #37, 1941; Gouache and pencil on paper; 8 x 6 inches (Box 1, Folder 1)
      On bottom left: "Gilbert Atencio 11"
    - Atencio, Gilbert Benjamin (Wah Peen). Left: [Walking man, sketch for drawing on right]. #33 Right: [Pueblo Man and Woman with basket on her head watching]. #32, [circa 1941]; Pencil on paper; 6 x 4 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Caption near right image: "Gilbert Atencio, 11"
    - Atencio, Gilbert Benjamin (Wah Peen). [Pueblo grandmother carrying grandson]. #40, 1943; Gouache on paperboard; 11 x 9 inches (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Atencio, Gilbert Benjamin (Wah Peen). [Pueblo Katchina on a blanket]. #39, 1943; Gouache on paperboard; 11 x 9 inches (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Atencio, Gilbert Benjamin (Wah Peen). [Skunk and corn basket]. #38, 1943; Gouache on paperboard; 9 x 11 inches (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Atencio, Gilbert Benjamin (Wah Peen). [Female Pueblo Rainbow Dancer]. #42, 1944; Gouache on paperboard; 11 x 9 inches (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Atencio, Gilbert Benjamin (Wah Peen). [Pueblo clown with basket of fruit]. #41, 1944; Gouache on paperboard; 11 x 9 inches (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Atencio, Gilbert Benjamin (Wah Peen). [Female Pueblo clown in yellow manta with cane]. #35, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 11 x 9 inches (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Atencio, Gilbert Benjamin (Wah Peen). "Indian Wedding." #36, Undated; Pencil and crayon on paper; 7 x 9 inches (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Atencio, Pat (Koo Peen). [Home scene of Pueblo woman and child making pottery]. #43, Undated; Pencil and crayon on paper; 9 x 6 inches (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Awa Tsireh. [Owl attacking skunk]. #130, 1939; Gouache on paperboard; 9 x 11 inches (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Begay, Timothy. [Figure holding stretched animal]. #44, 1939; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 8 inches (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bushyhead, Allan (Nakowhoadoniulzi). [Cheyenne male dancer]. #45, 1937; Gouache on paperboard; 9 x 8 inches (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Cata, Simon. [Skunk with ear of green corn]. #48, 1941; Gouache on paperboard; 11 x 9 inches (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Cata, Simon. [Turquoise Pueblo man bending over rug with a rope]. #47, 1941; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 9 inches (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Dewey, Wilson. [Masked figure dancing near fire]. #50, 1939; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 8 inches (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Dewey, Wilson. [Apache Devil Dancer]. #51, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 12 x 10 inches (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Dewey, Wilson. [Apache grey spotted dancer]. #52, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 12 x 10 inches (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Dewey, Wilson. [Man sitting under blanket next to plant]. #53, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 8 inches (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - García, Carlos (Nana-Tsidé). [Two Pueblo Kachinas]. #60, 1937; Gouache on paperboard; 4 x 6 inches (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - García, Peter. [Man, likely playing a hoop game]. #61, 1943; Gouache on paper; 11 x 9 inches (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Signed: "Pete G."
      On verso: "3rd or 4th grade."
    - Gutiérrez, José Leandro (Kgoo Ya). [Male Pueblo Clown chasing a chicken]. #62, 1938; Gouache on paper; 8 x 9.5 inches (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Signed: "Koo-ya"
    - Herrera, Joe Hilario (See Ru). [Male Cochiti Bow and Arrow Dancer]. #63, 1939; Gouache on paper; 11.5 x 8.5 inches (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Herrera, Justino (Stimone). [Two Pueblo Kachinas picking tree branches outside adobe]. #64, 1937; Watercolor and pencil on paperboard; 4 x 6 inches (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Herrera, Justino (Stimone). [Male Cochiti Basket Dancer]. #65, 1939; Gouache on paperboard; 11.5 x 9 inches (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Herrera, Justino (Stimone). [Pueblo masked woman with pot and tree branch]. #66, 1939; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 8 inches (Box 4, Folder 26)
      Signed "Steven H."
    - Houser, Allan C. (Haozous). [Apache Devil Dancer]. #68, 1935-1936; Gouache on paper; 10 x 7.5 inches (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Johnson, Walter."Cha-be-yo." #75, 1937; Gouache and pencil on paperboard; 6 x 4 inches (Box 4, Folder 28)
      Signed: "W.J"
      On verso: "Age: 13"
    - Martinez, Santana Roybal. "San Ildefonso pueblo pottery design." #131, 1922; Gouache on paperboard; 9.5 x 9 inches (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Pop Chalee. [Running horses and foxes]. #82, 1936; Gouache on paperboard; 8 x 9.5 inches (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Pop Chalee. [Mounted hare hunter]. #84, 1936; Gouache on paperboard; 8 x 9 inches (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Pop Chalee. "Shusshe would never drink water except from his cup." #85, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 8.5 x 7.5 inches (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Pop Chalee. "The pony did not like the smell of bear." #86, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 8.5 x 9 inches (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Unidentified. [Pueblo Kachina dancer with bow and arrow]. Verso: [Pueblo Kachina chasing man]. #25-26, Undated; Crayon and pencil on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - 17.5" x 11.75" Boxes
    - Hinds, Patrick Swazo. [Pueblo Deer Dancer]. #137, 1939; Gouache on paperboard; 11.5 x 9 inches (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Hinds, Patrick Swazo. [Galloping black horse]. #138, 1939-1940; Gouache on paperboard; 8 x 10 inches (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Keahbone, George Campbell. [Abstract of two skunks eating berries]. #78, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 9.5 x 11.5 inches (Box 5, Folder 37)
      On verso: "1940 Kiowa in Taos"
    - Luján, Alfred L.. [Running buffalos]. #81, 1936; Gouache on paperboard; 8 x 9.5 inches (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Martínez, Phillip. [Rabbits and birds]. #94, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 9.5 x 12 inches (Box 5, Folder 39)
      On verso: "3rd or 4th grade"
    - Mirabel, Eva (Eah Ha Wa). [Male Pueblo dancer]. #100, 1941; Gouache on paperboard; 8 x 9.5 inches (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Mirabel, Eva (Eah Ha Wa). [Pueblo man linking bundle of red blue and yellow corn]. #99, 1941; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 7.5 inches (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Mirabel, Eva (Eah Ha Wa). [Pueblo woman carrying basket of blue corn on her head]. #98, 1941; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 7.5 inches (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Mirabel, Eva (Eah Ha Wa). [Pueblo woman shucking blue corn]. #97, 1941; Gouache on paperboard; 8 x 9.5 inches (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Mirabel, Vicente (Chiu Tah). [Marching Kachina with branch]. #101, 1944; Gouache on Paperboard; 11 x 8.5 inches (Box 5, Folder 44)
      On verso: "This brings my holiday wishes to you both with much affection. / Leonard I. / If Frances should be with you she is heartily included. / Silk screened for their Christmas card 1944."
    - Mitchell, Stanley C. (Che Chilly Tsosie). [Navajo contemporary social couples dance]. #102, 1937; Gouache on paperboard; 8 x 9.5 inches (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Montoya, Gerónima Cruz (Po Tsunu). "Butterfly Dancer." #103, 1942; Gouache on paperboard; 12 x 9.5 inches (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Montoya, Gerónima Cruz (Po Tsunu). "Matachina Dancer." #104, 1942; Gouache on paperboard; 12 x 9.5 inches (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Montoya, Severiano. [Grey horse]. #105, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 9.5 x 10 inches (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Naranjo, Adolph (Ogowee). [Three dancing and singing Pueblo Clowns]. #107, 1939; Gouache on paperboard; 8 x 9.5 inches (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Nash, Wesley. [Apache Crown Dancer]. #109, 1943; Gouache on paperboard; 9 x 8 inches (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Nash, Wesley. "Devil Dancer." #110, 1943; Gouache on paperboard; 10.5 x 10.5 inches (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Nash, Wesley. [Apache Devil Dancer 1]. #108, 1945; Gouache on paperboard; 9 x 10.5 inches (Box 6, Folder 52)
      Signed: "Wes Nash '45"
    - Nash, Wesley. [Apache Devil Dancer 2]. #111, 1943; Gouache on paperboard; 9.5 x 10.5 inches (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Palmer, Ignatious. [Donkey in a marsh]. #112, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 12 x 9.5 inches (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Pavenyowma, Kenneth. [Pinto horse eating plant]. #113, 1941; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 8 inches (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Peña, Tonita (Quah Ah). "Cochiti Pueblo Mountain Sheep Dance." #114, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 15 x 11 inches (Box 6, Folder 56)
      Signed: "Quah Ah. Tonita Peña."
    - Peña, Tonita (Quah Ah). [Pueblo woman dancer with white pot and evergreens]. #115, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 14 x 11 inches (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Po-Povi Da. [Skunk with growing corn and black pot of corn]. #119, 1939-1940; Gouache on paperboard; 9.5 x 11.5 inches (Box 6, Folder 58)
      On verso: "Po-Povi (Water Flower) / San Ildefonso Pueblo / Box 172 / Santa Fe, N.M."
    - Po-Povi Da. [Sun over two skunks and corn basket]. #117, 1939-1940; Gouache on paperboard; 9.5 x 11.5 inches (Box 6, Folder 59)
      On verso: "Po Povi (Water Flower) / San Ildefonso Pueblo / Rt #1 Box 172"
    - Po-Povi Da. [Two skunks with a yellow flower]. #118, 1939-1940; Gouache on paperboard; 7.5 x 10 inches (Box 6, Folder 60)
      On verso: "Po-Povi (Water Flower) / San Ildefonso Pueblo / Box 172 Santa Fe, N.M."
    - Po-Povi Da. [Skunk with cactus and red flowers]. #120, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 9.5 x 11.5 inches (Box 6, Folder 61)
      On verso: "Po-Povi (Water Flower) / San Ildefonso Pueblo / Santa Fe, N. Mex. Box 172"
    - Po-Povi Da. [Rain cloud over skunk squirrel and corn basket]. #116, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 12 inches (Box 6, Folder 62)
      On verso: "Po-Po (Water Flower) / San Ildefonso Pueblo / Rt #1 Box 172"
    - Quintana, Ben (Ha A Tee). [Male Pueblo Buffalo Dancer]. #121, 1936; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 7.5 inches (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Quintana, Ben (Ha A Tee). [Orange and white spotted figure with broken watermelon]. #122, 1936; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 7 inches (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Quintana, Ben (Ha A Tee). [Pueblo drummer/singer]. #123, 1937; Gouache on paperboard; 9.5 x 7.5 inches (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Quintana, Ben (Ha A Tee). [Rain clouds over skunk]. #124, 1937; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 7.5 inches (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Quintana, Ben (Ha A Tee). [Two men sitting back to back on a donkey]. #125, 1937-1938; Gouache on paperboard; 8 x 9 inches (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Quintana, Ben (Ha A Tee). "Burro with wood." #126, 1938-1939; Gouache on paperboard; 10.5 x 7.5 inches (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Quintana, Ben (Ha A Tee). [Deer eating snow]. #127, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 9 x 7.5 inches (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - Quintana, Joe A. [Skunk family with growing fern and a frog]. #129, 1939; Gouache on paperboard; 9.5 x 11.5 inches (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Quintana, Joe A. [White and grey spotted figure with broken watermelon]. #128, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 8 inches (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Shelton, [Henry?] [Pueblo Kachina doll, pot and rattle displayed on quilt]. #135, 1943; Gouache on paperboard; 12 x 9 inches (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Suina, Theodore (Ku-pe-ru). "Buffalo Dancer." #136, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 11.5 x 9 inches (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Tahoma, Quincy. [Eagle and fawn]. #143, November 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 8 inches (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Tahoma, Quincy. [Leaping deer]. #139, November 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 8 x 10.5 inches (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Tahoma, Quincy. [Mother and bear cub with fish]. #141, November 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 8 inches (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Tahoma, Quincy. [Navajo old man riding burro]. #144, November 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 8 inches (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Tahoma, Quincy. [Three geese flying over marsh]. #142, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 8 inches (Box 7, Folder 78)
      On verso: "Age 19"
    - Tahoma, Quincy. [Two skunks with ears of corn]. #140, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 8 inches (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Tahoma, Quincy. [Pinto horse]. #145, 1941; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 7.5 inches (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Toldeo, Nicholas. [Prancing grey horse]. #147, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 10.5 x 8 inches (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - Vigil, Pete. [Kachina with hunted rabbit]. #148, 1937; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 7.5 inches (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Vigil, Utimio. [Deer, butterfly, birds and unknown animal, possibly beaver or bear]. #149, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 9 x 11 inches (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Unidentified. "Buffalo Dancers." On verso: "Navanjigi-la'n-cah (tearing the shirt) Wah-was's-Katchina (Racer)." #8 & #9, Undated; Pencil and crayon on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Unidentified. [Sketch of Kachina with smaller figure]. On verso: [Sketch of Kachina with stick]. #19 & #20, Undated; Pencil on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - Unidentified. [Sketch of Kachina carrying child in a basket]. #27, Undated; Pencil on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - Unidentified. [Turkey on branch]. #28, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 9 x 11 inches (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - Unidentified. [Clown dancing with stick and bird feathers]. #29, 1939; Gouache on paperboard; 11 x 9 inches (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - 20.5" x 17.5" Boxes
    - Abeyta, Domingo. "Indian dance." #1, 1919; Pencil and crayon on paper; 8 x 11.5 inches (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - Abeyta, Domingo. [Four types of Pueblo dance and drummers]. #2, 1919; Pencil and crayon on paper; 8 x 11.5 inches (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - Abeyta, Domingo. [Observed Buffalo Dance]. On verso: [Three Indian hunters]. #3 & #4, 1919-1920; Pencil and crayon on paper; 8 x 11.5 inches (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Annahoho. "This figure comes with the whippers." #5, 1920; Gouache on paper; 11 x 15 inches (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - [Atencio?], Gilbert [Benjamin?]. [Women putting on buckskin leggings]. #34, Undated; Pencil and crayon on paper; 9 x 11 inches (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Calabaza, Santiago. [Three Indian figures]. #46, 1919; Pencil and watercolor on paper; 8 x 12 inches (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - Crispin, Santiago. [Three types of Pueblo dance and drummers]. #49, 1919; Pencil and crayon on paper; 8 x 12 inches (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "Three generations of Zia Pueblo women, painted by 15 year old boy." #67, 1919; Gouache on paper; 9.5 x 12.5 inches (Box 9, Folder 96)
      On verso: "Property of E. W. DeHuff / U. S. Indian School / Santa Fe, N. M."
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). [Woman waving stick at window of building with on looking small creature]. #164, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 15 x 11 inches (Box 9, Folder 97)
      Annotated in pencil
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). [Man shedding bear skin and coming out of cave]. #165, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 14 x 11 inches (Box 9, Folder 98)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). [Nature scene of a bird on branch, a lizard on a rock, and a pot on a fire]. #166, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 14 x 11 inches (Box 9, Folder 99)
      Engraving company plate slip attached to verso
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). [Family scene with table of food]. #167, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 9, Folder 100)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). [Old man placing hoop over the head of a shapeshifter]. #168, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 9, Folder 101)
      Annotated in pencil (erased but still legible)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). [Crying coyote with three birds]. #169, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 9, Folder 102)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). [Scaled giant holding Indian man]. #170, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 103)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). [Scaled giant running and being attacked with arrows by two Indian men]. #171, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 14 x 11 inches (Box 10, Folder 104)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "Velino Hererra's illustration for New Mexico Magazine ." #172, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14.5 inches (Box 10, Folder 105)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "The Twins took offerings of corn meal and tobacco to Gopher-man to solicit his aid." #173, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 106)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "One of the Comanches found Maria beneath the altar and dragged her out by the hair." #174, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 107)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "The Deer began to trip in the holes that Gopher-man had made along his race course." #175, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 108)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "Children's tales (1)." #185, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 109)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "Children's tales (2)." #176, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 110)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "The white locust went out to bore his way through the hard ground on a tour of investigation. He found water everywhere." #177, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 111)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "As the women crossed the river to join the men, the Coyote stole the baby the Water Spirit." #178, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 112)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "In solemn procession, the Indians took the image of the Christ Child around their corn fields." #179, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 113)
      Annotated in Pencil
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "First Woman covered the things she had gathered together to create the Navajo and covered them with a blanket of mists." #180, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 114)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "When First Woman took off the blanket of mist, there were the first Navajos." #181, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 115)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "Navajo tale in creation myth 1." #186, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 116)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "Navajo tale in creation myth 2." #187, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 117)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "Navajo tale in creation myth 3 (story of gambling in moccasin game)." #182, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 10, Folder 118)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "Snake Dance legend 1." #183, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 14 x 11 inches (Box 11, Folder 119)
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). "Snake Dance legend 2." #184, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 11, Folder 120)
    - Kabotie, Fredie. "Tu-ni-li'-ni (Navajo word)." Verso: "Oo-wah-nah-zoozoo (Katchina that crushes stones with his mouth)." #76 & 77, 1938; Pencil and crayon on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 11, Folder 121)
      Annotation: "Sketches by Fredie Kabotie, son of Fred Kabotie at the age of 6 yrs."
    - Kokw'e'le. "This is a man dressed as a girl and dances in the sacred rain during the summer." #79, [circa 1920]; Gouache and pencil on paper; 15 x 11 inches (Box 11, Folder 122)
    - Martínez, Adam. [Three chickens fighting for corn under a rainbow]. #87, 1942 May; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 13 inches (Box 11, Folder 123)
    - Martínez, Adam. [Black chicken and brown chicken arguing]. #88, 1942 May; Gouache on paperboard; 10 x 13 inches (Box 11, Folder 124)
    - Martínez, Adam. [Skunk and deer]. #89, Undated; Gouache and pencil on paperboard; 10 x 13 inches (Box 11, Folder 125)
    - Martínez, Julián (Pho-Ca-No). [Two male Pueblo Comanche Dancers]. #90, [circa 1921]; Watercolor on paper; 11.5 x 14.5 inches (Box 11, Folder 126)
    - Martínez, Julián (Pho-Ca-No). [Two male Pueblo Eagle Dancers]. #91, [circa 1923]; Watercolor on paper; 10.5 x 14 inches (Box 11, Folder 127)
    - Martínez, Julián (Pho-Ca-No). [Snake attacking skunk]. #92, 1928; Watercolor on paper; 9 x 11 inches (Box 11, Folder 128)
    - Martínez, Julián (Pho-Ca-No). [Pueblo sun and spirit bird design]. #195, 1935; Gouache on paperboard; 15 x 12.5 inches (Box 11, Folder 129)
    - Martínez, Julián (Pho-Ca-No). [Clown holding a skunk]. #196, 1940; Gouache on paperboard; 15 x 15 inches (Box 11, Folder 130)
    - Martínez, Miguel. [Two male Pueblo Snake Dancers]. #93, [circa 1923]; Watercolor on paper; 10.5 x 14.5 inches (Box 11, Folder 131)
    - Martinez, Santana Roybal. "San Ildefonso pottery design (1)." #132, 1922; Gouache on paperboard; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 12, Folder 132)
      On verso: "Property of J. D. DeHuff / U. S. Indian School / Santa Fe, N. M."
    - Martinez, Santana Roybal. "San Ildefonso pottery design (2)." #133, 1922; Gouache on paperboard; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 12, Folder 133)
    - Martinez, Santana Roybal. "Bird (parrot) from a San Ildefonso pottery design." #134, 1922; Gouache on paperboard; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 12, Folder 134)
    - Martinez, Santana Roybal. [San Ildefonso Pueblo pottery design (3)]. #199, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 13.5 x 17 inches (Box 12, Folder 135)
    - Medina, R. "Zuni Pueblo Pottery Design (1)." # 95, 1922; Gouache on paperboard; 11 x 14.5 inches (Box 12, Folder 136)
      On verso: "Property of J. D. DeHuff / Government Indian School / Santa Fe, N.M."
    - Medina, R."Zuni Pueblo Pottery design (2)." #96, 1922; Gouache on paperboard; 11 x 14.5 inches (Box 12, Folder 137)
      On verso: "Property of J. D. DeHuff / Government Indian School / Santa Fe, N. M."
    - Moquino, Juanito. [Forest scene with deer and squirrel]. #106, 1930; Watercolor on paperboard; 14.5 x 11 inches (Box 12, Folder 138)